<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Charity &#8211; Public Services Muslims Association of Ghana</title>
	<atom:link href="https://psmagh.org/post/category/charity/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://psmagh.org</link>
	<description>Welcome to Public Services Muslims Association of Ghana Website</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 11:57:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://psmagh.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Charity &#8211; Public Services Muslims Association of Ghana</title>
	<link>https://psmagh.org</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Power of Giving: Why Contributions and Donations to PSMAG Matter</title>
		<link>https://psmagh.org/post/2023/02/the-power-of-giving-why-contributions-and-donations-to-psmag-matter/</link>
					<comments>https://psmagh.org/post/2023/02/the-power-of-giving-why-contributions-and-donations-to-psmag-matter/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 18:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Charity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://psmagh.org/?p=4484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Contributions and donations play a crucial role in the success of any organisation, and the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Contributions and donations play a crucial role in the success of any organisation, and the Public Services Muslims Association of Ghana (PSMAG) is no exception. By making contributions and donations, individuals can support the important work of the Association and help to ensure its continued success. We will discuss why contributions and donations to the Association are so important, and what impact they can have.</p>



<p>One of the main reasons for making contributions and donations to PSMAG is to help support its mission. The Association seeks to promote the developmental, religious, social and general welfare of all Muslim Public Servants in Ghana. By making contributions and donations, individuals can help to ensure that these goals are achieved and that the Association can continue to do important work.</p>



<p>Furthermore, making contributions and donations is to demonstrate a commitment to the community. By making a financial commitment to the Association, individuals can show their support for the work that the Association does and the impact it has. This not only helps to sustain the Association, but it also sends a message of unity and support to other members of the Muslim community.</p>



<p>The Qur&#8217;an and Hadiths also emphasize the importance of giving and supporting good causes. In Surah Al-Baqarah, verse 254, the Qur&#8217;an states, <strong>&#8220;And spend from what We have provided you before death approaches one of you and he says, &#8216;My Lord, if only You would delay me for a brief term so I would give charity and be among the righteous.'&#8221;</strong> This verse throws light on the idea that giving and supporting good causes is a critical aspect of the Islam. Additionally, the Prophet Muhammad (peace be upon him) said in a Hadith, <strong>&#8220;The best form of charity is to give while one is still alive.&#8221;</strong> This Hadith emphasises the idea that giving and supporting good causes is a way of making a positive impact on humanity and ensuring a better future for all.</p>



<p>Contributions and donations to the Association play a crucial role in ensuring its success and making a positive impact on the Muslim community. By making a financial commitment, we can support the important work of the Association, demonstrate our commitment to the community. So, let us give generously to the Association and help ensure its continued success.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://psmagh.org/post/2023/02/the-power-of-giving-why-contributions-and-donations-to-psmag-matter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
